Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
Henry Miller papers
1896-1984
1930-1980
UCLA Library Special Collections
Miller, Henry
LSC.0110
76.0 linear feet (144 boxes, 2 cartons, 5 shoe boxes, and 15 oversize boxes)
Henry Miller (1891-1980) was a prominent American writer and artist. This collection of his personal papers contains correspondence, manuscripts, legal documents, printed materials, film and audio recordings, and original artwork.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Henry Miller, 1945-1979. Also includes gifts from Bern Porter, Emil Schnellock, Hilaire Hiler, Gerald Robitaille and Barbara Miller, 1945-1988; and miscellaneous manuscript purchases, 1989-1998.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942334193606533
Biographical / Historical
Henry Valentine Miller was born December 26, 1891 in Manhattan to Heinrich Miller and Louise Nieting. A year later, the family moved to Brooklyn where Miller spent the majority of his childhood and adolescence. After graduating from high school in 1909, Miller attended the City College of New York for two months before leaving school. Throughout his twenties, Miller had a series of odd jobs, and in 1913 he left New York and traveled west, working briefly in California before he returned home to work in his father's tailor shop. In 1917 Miller married Beatrice Sylvan Wickens, and their first daughter, Barbara, was born two years later. At this time, Miller started working for Western Union Telegraph company where he made his first serious attempts at writing. Miller met June Edith Smith (June Mansfield) at a dance hall in 1923, and they were married in 1924 following a divorce from his first wife. At this time, Miller quit his job at Western Union in order to devote his time to writing, a decision that left him in poverty for much of this period. Miller and June traveled to Europe in 1928. Miller returned to Europe again in 1930 with the intention of living there permanently. He settled in Paris, where he would spend the majority of the next ten years, and immediately began writing Tropic of Cancer. This became his first published book in 1934. In Paris, Miller became involved in the literary and artistic scene, befriending writers and artists such as Alfred Perle's, Michael Frankel, Abraham Rattner, Hans Reichel, and Lawrence Durrell. Miller met Anaïs Nin in 1931, and both a romantic relationship and a lasting literary friendship developed. Miller was divorced from his second wife, June, in 1934. At the invitation of his friend Lawrence Durrell, Miller traveled to Greece in 1939, a trip that inspired his famous work, The Colossus of Maroussi. He was forced to return to the United States in 1940 as a result of the war in Europe. After his return, Miller lived in Los Angeles. During these years, Miller had several watercolor exhibitions in Los Angeles and London and prepared more of his writings for publication. In 1944, Miller married Janina Lepska, a graduate student who he had met on a trip to New York, and the Millers moved to Big Sur that same year. Daughter Valentine was born in 1945, and son Tony was born in 1948. Miller separated from Lepska in 1951. In 1953, Miller and Eve McClure toured Europe together; on their return, Miller and Eve were married. They divorced in 1960. In 1961 Tropic of Cancer was published for the first time in the United States, and censorship battles began. It wasn't until 1964 that the Supreme Court of the United States ruled that the book was not pornographic. The stateside publication of Tropic of Cancer made Miller famous in the United States, and a steady stream of fans began to visit and write to him at his home in Big Sur. In an attempt to flee the constant attention, Miller moved to Pacific Palisades in 1962 where he lived for the remainder of his life. In 1966, Miller met Hiroko "Hoki" Tokuda, a Japanese nightclub singer. They were married that same year, but Hoki left Miller in 1977. Miller continued to write, but poor eyesight and health problems decreased the frequency. He did, however, continue to produce watercolors until his death. Miller died at the age of 88 on June 7, 1980.
Scope and Content
The Henry Miller Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, printed materials, film, audio recordings, and artwork that document Henry Miller's life and career as a writer and painter. The collection contains a large body of correspondence, primarily from Miller's friends, fans, and members of his artistic and literary circles, including Brassaï, Blaise Cendrars, Lawrence Durrell, Alfred Perle's, Abraham Rattner, Anaïs Nin, Bezalel Schatz, and Jean Verame. Of particular interest are the original manuscripts for many of Miller's books, essays, articles, and reviews that span the whole of his career as a writer, including several early, unpublished manuscripts dating from the late 1920s. The collection also includes a large selection of original watercolors by Miller and artwork given to Miller by friends and prominent artists, including Man Ray, Abram Krol and Gyula Zilzer. Other significant materials include legal documents related to court proceedings involving the publication of Tropic of Cancer, ephemera documenting Miller's publications and art exhibitions, copies of films of or related to Miller, sound recordings of Miller reading from various works including Tropic of Capricorn, and photographs of Miller and his art.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence, 1899-1980 (95 boxes), subseries A-J as follows:
1A. Main correspondence
1B-1J. Deposited correspondence
Manuscripts, 1896-1980 (37 boxes, 2 oversized boxes), subseries A-C as follows:
2A. Literary manuscripts by Miller
2B. Prefaces and reviews by Miller
2C. Manuscripts by others
Microfilm, 1933-1959 (5 shoeboxes)
Photographs, 1891-1978 (1 box, 1 oversized box)
Printed materials, 1937-1984 (14 boxes), subseries A-D as follows:
5A. Ephemera
5B. News clippings
5C. Legal materials
5D. Extracts from periodicals
Artwork, 1931-1980 (9 oversized boxes), subseries A-C as follows:
6A. Original artwork by Miller
6B. Artwork by others
6C. Signed prints and posters
Audio and visual materials, 1944-1973 (1 box, 3 oversized boxes), subseries A-B as follows:
7A. Sound recordings
7B. Films.
Related Materials
Henry Miller 84: A Video Portrait, by John Hunt in Miscellaneous manuscripts (LSC 100). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Books from Henry Miller's library that were originally donated with the papers have been individually cataloged in the UCLA Library online catalog. Records for these items may be found by searching on the keywords, "Henry Miller former owner."
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Manuscripts for publication; Paintings (visual works).; Artists -- United States -- Archives.; Miller, Henry -- Archives; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert)
- Correspondence, 1899-1980; 95 boxes (47.5 linear ft.)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series primarily consists of letters to Henry Miller. Major types of correspondents include fans, publishers, friends and acquaintances, and members of Miller's literary and intellectual circles. In the instances where a folder contains a draft of an outgoing letter by Miller, it has been noted in the folder description. After 1969, correspondence was deposited with UCLA in yearly increments and remained separate from the primary correspondence. Materials arrived unsorted, grouped together by year.
  Arranged in subseries A-J as follows:
  A. Main correspondence, ca. 1899-1980 (68 boxes)
  B. Deposited correspondence, 1968-1969 (2 boxes)
  C. Deposited correspondence, 1970 (3 boxes)
  D. Deposited correspondence, 1971 (3 boxes)
  E. Deposited correspondence, 1972 (3 boxes)
  F. Deposited correspondence, 1973 (2 boxes)
  G. Deposited correspondence, 1974 (2 boxes)
  H. Deposited correspondence, 1975 (3 boxes)
  I. Deposited correspondence, 1976 (2 boxes)
  J. Deposited correspondence, 1977-1979 (7 boxes).
  - Main correspondence, ca. 1899-1980; 68 boxes (34 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, primarily donated by Henry Miller to the UCLA Library before 1969. Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the correspondent, and chronologically within single correspondents. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet.
    - A/S Bookman--Acford, 1949-1968; 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abramson, Ben [Argus Book Shop], 1941-1957; 63 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Henry Miller and Bern Porter.
    - Ackroyd, Graham, 1949-1969; 86 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adam--Adnan, 1946-1969; 25 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adriani, Bruno, 1946-1958; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aeschbad--Albaugh, 1947-1967; 23 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Albers, Heinz, 1948-1956; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Albert--Allen, G., 1945-1968; 39 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allen, John Houghton--Allen, John R., 1957-1963; 17 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Allen, La Verne--Allen, Steve, 1952-1969; 12 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Allen, William, 1947-1961; 71 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allen, William--Amzalem, 1946-1969; 58 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anderberg--Anderson, Ron, 1954-1968; 18 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Anderson, Sherwood--Anderson, Thomas, circa 1940-1967; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Anderson, Wendell, 1944-1945; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Anderson, Wiilliam--Angst, 1946-1968; 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Angulo, Jaime de, 1923-1956; 24 items. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Anh--L'Arc en Ciel, 1949-1969; 44 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Arche Publishing--Armanaseo, 1949-1967; 42 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Armitage, Merle, 1946-1957; 31 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Armkrup, Benke, 1962 September 8; 1 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Armstrong, Neville, 1955-1956; 18 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Army Academy--Arnold, 1955-1968; 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Arnold, William, 1963-1968; 44 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Arnon--Arroyo, 1948-1968; 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Arschot, Ruby d', 1956-1957; 16 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Arsenault--ARTFORUM, 1956-1964; 12 items. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Arthur, Chester, 1926; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Artinian--Association for Research and Enlightenment, 1947-1966; 37 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Association Generale--Atterton, 1946-1967; 16 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Aubray, Therese, 1937; 12 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Audio Workshop--Augstein, 1947-1963; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ault, Bill, 1949-1950; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Auray--Azcona, 1947-1968; 34 items. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Baas--Baff, 1945-1968; 21 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bagby, Jack Lee and Jeanne, 1955-1958; 29 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bahl--Bailey, 1959-1965; 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Baird, John N., 1947; 12 items. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Baisden--Baldote, 1943-1968; 27 items. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Baldwin, James, 1963 May 30; 1 items. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Baldwin, Teresa--Barclift, 1946-1967; 39 items. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Barefoot--Baron, 1948-1965; 45 items. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Baron, Oscar, 1945-1957; 19 items. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Baron, Richard--Barrie, 1952-1964; 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Barron, Louis and Bebe, 1949-1950; 13 items. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Barrows, George S., 1946-1960; 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Barry--Bate, 1943-1968; 38 items. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bateman--Baxter, Ann, 1945-1968; 37 items. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Baxter, Annette and James, 1952-1967; 39 items. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Baxter, Jim--Becher, 1949-1968; 25 items. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Becker, Edwin, 1945-1954; 39 items. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Becker Travel Bureau, Inc.--Beigel, 1951-1967; 35 items. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Beiss, Beth, 1957; 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bejean--Bellow, 1945-1968; 35 items. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Belmont, Georges, 1951-1969; 55 items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Beloit Poetry Journal--Berch, 1949-1966; 34 items. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Bercut--Bernstein, Arthur, 1945-1968; 52 items. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bernstein, Leon L., 1948-1950; 22 items. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Berntsen--Bertrand, Claude Jean, 1947-1967; 23 items. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Bertrand, Raoul, 1948-1968; 45 items. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bertuch, Edwin and Ingeborg, 1944-1957; 24 items. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Beston--Beul-Andersen, 1946-1969; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Beutel, Gottfried, 1947-1948; 18 items. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Bewick--Bianchi, 1957-1963; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Bibalo, Antonio, 1960-1967; 59 items. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale--Bird, circa 1935-1969; 53 items. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Birge, Vincent (1 of 2), 1952-1954; 41 items. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Birge, Vincent (2 of 2), 1955-1968; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Birkbeck--Blair, 1940-1968; 38 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Blake--Blankenburg, 1960-1965; 7 items. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Blankinship, Earl H., 1954-1957; 32 items. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Blankmeister--Bloom, Don, 1950-1967; 17 items. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bloom, Roger (1 of 4), 1956-1961; 105 items. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bloom, Roger (2 of 4), 1962-1965; 89 items. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Bloom, Roger (3 of 4 ), 1965-1967; 40 items. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bloom, Roger (4 of 4 ), 1967-1968; 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Blosser--Bluefarb, 1947-1968; 31 items. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Blum--Bonhage, 1947-1969; 61 items. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Bonnefoi--Boon, 1950-1968; 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Booster [French publication], 1937; 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bord--Bosarab, 1952-1969; 25 items. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bose--Boston University Library, 1954-1967; 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Boterf, Helene le, 1948-1953; 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Boucher--Boyea, 1950-1968; 48 items. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Boyle--Braroe, 1933-1966; 66 items. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Brassaï, Gyula Halasz, 1948-1967; 103 items. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Brasset--Breton, Andre, 1947-1969; 61 items. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Breton, Jean--Broadside Magazine, 1943-1969; 72 items. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Broadway--Brooklyn Museum, 1946-1967; 12 items. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Public Library, 1945-1956; 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Brooks--Brown, Don, 1945-1967; 47 items. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Brown, F.J., undated; 4 items. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Francis--Browning, 1949-1968; 32 items. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Bruckberger, (Pere) Raymond Leopold, 1948-1957; 24 items. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Brumagne, Marie--Magdeleine, 1958-1962; 16 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Brumbaugh--Buckholz, 1944-1968; 72 items. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Buckley, Richard, 1955-1961; 28 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Buckley, T.J.--Buettner, 1947-1967; 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Bufano--Bugacoff Bugacoff, Jorge 1963 December 1, 1940-1969; 48 items. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bukowski, Charles, 1965 August; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Buland--Burkhalter, 1932-1968; 42 items. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Burliuk, David, 1954-1956; 16 items. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Burnett--Bush, 1950-1969; 40 items. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bushko--Byron, 1950-1968; 41 items. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Cabarga--Cainus, 1957-1965; 11 items. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cairns, Huntington [General Counsel to the National Gallery], 1938-1960; 65 items. (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Includes two letters to Cairns by Henry Miller, one from written from France in 1939, and the other from Big Sur in 1944.
    - Calavetta--California State Board of Equalization, 1945-1963; 15 items. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - California State College Los Angeles--Callahan California State Department of Education, 1949-1965; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Callow--Calmer, 1951-1960; 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Camargo, Constanza, 1965-1966; 32 items. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cambria Books--Camera Craft, 1952-1960; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cameron, David [plus Hildegaard Knepf], 1961-1969; 34 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Camilly--Campbell, Bob, 1952-1965; 22 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Campbell, Margaret--The Carleton Miscellany, 1947-1968; 41 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Carlier--Carlisle, 1950-1959; 12 items. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Carlock, Bob, 1949-1957; 41 items. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Carlson--Cassel, 1944-1969; 67 items. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Cassmore--Cemoius, 1955-1969; 41 items. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Cendrars, Blaise, 1947-1958; 83 items. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Cendrars, Miriam, 1949-1963; 12 items. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cendron--Chadwick, 1945-1973; 19 items. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Chagall, Marc, 1948; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Chakovskoi, Elie, 1948-1958; 18 items. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Chamberlain--Chang, 1948-1966; 23 items. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Chapdelaine--Chicago Review, 1950-1969; 44 items. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Chicago University Art Committee--Chidsey, 1945-1964; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Childs, J. Rives, 1953-1965; 51 items. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Chilton--Chung, 1946-1966; 32 items. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Church, W. Howard, 1955-1961; 19 items. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Churchill--Cioran, 1948-1962; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Cison--Clayton, 1940-1969; 50 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cleaire--Cloos, 1949-1968; 39 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Close--Coe, 1946-1964; 47 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Coercion Review--Collier, 1929-1968; 61 items. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Collingwood Publishing Co.--Colt, 1943-1967; 15 items. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Colt Press, 1941-1943; 8 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Columbia Pictures Corporation--Constable, 1941-1968; 56 items. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Constantinore--Coram, 1945-1977; 28 items. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Corbett, June, 1942-1962; 83 items. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Cordemans--Cordry, 1960; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Corle, Edwin [Armitage Books], 1947-1956; 38 items. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Corle, Jean--Corrace, 1948-1968; 25 items. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Correa & Co., Editions [publishers], 1953-1956; 74 items. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Cortes--Cory, 1948-1962; 29 items. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Cossery, Albert, 1945-1950; 10 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Costa--Cowles, 1945-1969; 41 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cowley--Cramer, Neill, 1948-1965; 22 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Cramer, Susanne, 1964-1966; 16 items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Crampton, Savington, 1943-1969; 20 items. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Includes lengthy letters from Henry Miller.
    - Crandall--Creeley, 1940-1955; 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Crehan--Crews, Fred, 1946-1960; 16 items. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Crews, Judson, 1944-1957; 67 items. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Criel, Gaston, 1950-1955; 12 items. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Includes one letter from Henry Miller.
    - Crist Book Shop--Cromwell, 1956-1965; 12 items. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Crosby, Caresse, 1948-1968; 40 items. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Crosland--Cummings, John, 1950-1968; 37 items. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Cummings, Ridgely, 1949-1951; 17 items. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Cunningham Press--Czerniak, 1953-1968; 28 items. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Daco--Danner, 1948-1969; 49 items. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Daour--Dawson's Book Shop, 1939-1967; 56 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Day--de Kooster, 1953-1966; 48 items. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - De Laney, Beauford, 1944-1967; 88 items. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - De Magnin--de Rachewiltz, 1960-1965; 21 items. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - De Roin--Del, 1942-1965; 38 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Del Mar Book Store--Delpino, 1948-1965; 27 items. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Delteil, Joseph and Caroline Dudley, 1955-1959; 46 items. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Deltjeir--Dempster, 1945-1969; 14 items. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Denat, Antoine H., 1954-1966; 24 items. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Dendridge--Devaux, 1948-1968; 33 items. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Devil in Paradise, 1956; 135 items. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Devilbiss--Devimendian, 1953-1964; 10 items. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Dewar, William [attorney], 1935-1965; 19 items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Dewey--Diamond, 1951-1968; 17 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Dibbern Family, 1947-1962; 28 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Dibbern, George, 1945-1962; ca. 100 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Henry Miller.
    - Dice--Dickman, 1948-1967; 9 items. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Dickson, Edward Pratt, 1950-1958; 48 items. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Dickson--Dobelis, 1952-1968; 24 items. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Dobo, Francis F., 1937-1965; 35 items. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Dochnon--Donau Verlag [publisher], 1946-1968; 14 items. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Doner--Dosick, 1950-1969; 61 items. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Doubleday & Co. Inc., 1944-1966; 26 items. (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Includes contract for Air Conditioned Nightmare, and a draft of a letter by Henry Miller.
    - Doublet--Draper, 1953-1966; 24 items. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dreihoek, De, Uitgeverij [publisher], 1947-1950; 13 items. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dreis--Duclos, 1944-1968; 25 items. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Dudley, John, circa 1940s; 25 items. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Duell, Sloan, and Pearce, Inc., 1947-1952; 25 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Duhamel--Dunfee, 1948-1965; 27 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Dunkin, Ronald Allen, 1957-1961; 26 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dunlap--Durham, 1939-1967; 12 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (01 of 14), 1936; 15 items. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (02 of 14), 1937; 35 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (03 of 14), 1938; 10 items. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (04 of 14), 1939; 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (05 of 14), 1940; 10 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Includes three letters to Anaïs Nin.
    - Durrell, Lawrence (06 of 14), 1944-1945; 15 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (07 of 14), 1945-1947; 16 items. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (08 of 14), 1947-1948; 17 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (09 of 14), 1949-1952; 25 items. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (10 of 14), 1953-1956; 16 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (11 of 14), 1957-1959; 70 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Includes letters between Durrell, Miller, and James Laughlin re. the Henry Miller Reader. Also includes letters between Durrell, Alfred Perlès and Miller later published in Art and Outrage.
    - Durrell, Lawrence (12 of 14), 1959; 40 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (13 of 14), 1961; 10 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Durrell, Lawrence (14 of 14), 1963-1977; 126 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Dussart--Dynbort, 1956-1967; 31 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Eagan--Eastman, 1951-1969; 27 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Eastwood--Editions de la Licorne, 1948-1967; 42 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Editions Denoel, Les, 1946-1958; 64 items. (Box 14, Folder 9)